A Guide to the Papers of Louisa May Alcott 1848 (1863-1888) 1956
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer 1888 February 8, ALS with envelope 8 p. (Box-folder 2:120)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. January 13, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:121)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. January 15, ALS with envelope 2 p. (Box-folder 2:122)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. February 10, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:123)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. February 12, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:124)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura [Hosmer] n.y. February 18, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:125)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. February 20, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:126)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. April 22, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:127)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. [May 1], ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:128)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. [May 11], ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:129)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer with transcript n.y. [June 17], ALS with envelope 1 p. (Box-folder 2:130)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. July 3, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:131)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. July 14, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:132)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. July 15, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:133)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. [July 26], ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:134)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. [July] 27, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:135)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. July 31, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:136)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. August 3, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:137)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. September 5, ALS with envelope 3 p. (Box-folder 2:138)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. September 16, ALS with envelope 1 p. (Box-folder 2:139)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. October 20, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:140)
  - [Louisa May Alcott] to Laura Hosmer n.y. November 16, envelope. (Box-folder 2:141)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. November 23, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:142)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. [December 8], ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:143)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.y. [December 24], ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:144)
  - Louisa May Alcott and Anna Pratt to Laura Hosmer n.y. December 25, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 2:145)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.d. [?] 15, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:146)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.d., ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:147)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.d., ALS with envelope 2 p. (Box-folder 2:148)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.d., ALS with envelope 2 p. (Box-folder 2:149)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer n.d., ALS with envelope 2 p. (Box-folder 2:150)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer "Monday", ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:151)
  - Louisa May Alcott and Anna Pratt to Laura Hosmer "Tuesday", ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:152)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer "Tuesday", ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:153)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer "Wednesday", ALS with envelope 3 p. (Box-folder 2:154)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer "Friday", ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:155)
  - James N. Hyde to Boston Commonwealth regarding hospital name in Sketches 1865 July 3, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:156)
  - "Joe" to Louisa May Alcott 1877 November 28, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:157)
  - Editor of Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper to Louisa May Alcott 1863, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:158)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mrs. Livermore 1876 November 22, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:159)
  - A.K. Loring to Louisa May Alcott 1864 September 30, ALS 7 p. (Box-folder 2:160)
  - A.K. Loring to Louisa May Alcott 1864 October 24, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:161)
  - A.K. Loring to Louisa May Alcott [1864], ALS 7 p. (Box-folder 2:162)
  - A.K. Loring to Louisa May Alcott 1881 August 19, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:163)
    regarding Moods rights with enclosures 1867-1872. 6255-b
  - A.K. Loring to Louisa May Alcott n.y. March 30, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 2:164)
  - A.K. Loring to Louisa May Alcott n.y. [Dec 24], ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:165)
  - A.K. Loring to Louisa May Alcott n.d., ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:166)
  - A.K. Loring to Louisa May Alcott n.d., ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:167)
  - A.K. Loring to Louisa May Alcott "Sunday", ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:168)
  - A.K. Loring to Louisa May Alcott "Friday", ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:169)
  - Louisa May Alcott to "Lou" [1887 December -], ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:170)
  - Louisa May Alcott to [Grace] Moshier n.y. April 6, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:171)
  - Louisa May Alcott to [Grace] Moshier n.y. October 12, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:172)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Miss Murdock [1887] November 15, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:173)
  - E. Nieriker to Louisa May Alcott 1884 September 15, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:174)
  - T. Niles to Louisa May Alcott 1870 January 12, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:175)
  - T. Niles to Louisa May Alcott 1870 February 17, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 2:176)
  - T. Niles to Louisa May Alcott 1876 April 3, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 2:177)
  - Louisa May Alcott to T. Niles [1886] October 3, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:178)
  - Louisa May Alcott to T. Niles [1887 June 23], ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 2:179)
  - Louisa May Alcott to T. Niles n.d., ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 2:180)
  - W[illiam] J. Niles to Louisa May Alcott 1870 May 31, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:181)
  - W[illiam] J. Niles to Louisa May Alcott 1871 March 3, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:182)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mrs. Norcross with photo of Louisa May Alcott n.y. October 14, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:183)
  - Christmas card: Louisa May Alcott to S.N. n.y. [December], Card 1 p. (Box-folder 2:184)
  - J.R. Osgood to Louisa May Alcott 1869 October 13, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:185)
  - L.D. Parker to Louisa May Alcott 1865 February 13, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:186)
  - Elizabeth P. Peabody to Anna Pratt [1888 March 8], ALS with address 2 p. (Box-folder 2:187)
  - Elizabeth P. Peabody to Louisa May Alcott n.d., ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:188)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mr. Plummer n.d., ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:189)
  - Emilie Poulsson to Louisa May Alcott 1882 February 24, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 2:190)
  - Louisa May Alcott to "N" [Anna Alcott Pratt] [1888], ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:191)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mrs. [Anna Alcott] Pratt n.y. March 20, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:192)
  - Louisa May Alcott to "Nan" [Anna Alcott Pratt] n.y. November 29, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:193)
  - Louisa May Alcott to "Nan" [Anna Alcott Pratt] n.d., ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:194)
  - Louisa May Alcott to "Nanny" [Anna Alcott Pratt] n.d., AL 8 p. (Box-folder 2:195)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mrs. Raymond n.d., ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:196)
    6255-i
  - James Redpath to Louisa May Alcott with memorandum 1863 June 26, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:197)
  - James Redpath to Louisa May Alcott 1863 August 8, AL fragment 2 p. (Box-folder 2:198)
  - James Redpath to Louisa May Alcott 1863 December 1, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:199)
  - James Redpath to Louisa May Alcott 1864 January 23, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:200)
  - James Redpath to Louisa May Alcott n.y. August 13, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:201)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Miss Richards n.d., ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:202)
  - F.M. Rockwell to Louisa May Alcott 1874 March 31, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:203)
  - 6255-b 1874 April 30, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:204)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mr. [Ropes] [1885] September 25, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:205)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Miss Russel n.y. July 13, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:206)
  - Louisa May Alcott with Sampson Low, Son & Marston 1872 May 31, AD acct 7 p. (Box-folder 2:207)
  - Sampson Low, Son & Marston to Louisa May Alcott 1879 December 30, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 2:208)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Scribner & Co. with transcript [1877] December 2, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:209)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Scribner & Co. with transcript n.y. December 10, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:210)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Scribner & Co. n.d., AL draft 3 p. (Box-folder 2:211)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Scribner & Co. n.d., AL draft 3 p. (Box-folder 2:212)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Miss Seymour with PS by her mother n.y. September 21, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:213)
  - Benj[amin] G. Smith to Louisa May Alcott 1867 June 13, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:214)
  - Benj[amin] G. Smith to Louisa May Alcott 1869 April 29, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:215)
  - Tauchnitz to Louisa May Alcott 1878 November 28, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:216)
  - Tauchnitz, Jr. to Louisa May Alcott 1882 November 13, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 2:217)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Tauchnitz n.d., AL copy 3 p. (Box-folder 2:218)
  - H[oward] M. Ticknor to Louisa May Alcott 1861 December 7, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 2:219)
  - H[oward] M. Ticknor to Louisa May Alcott 1861 December 10, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:220)
  - Ticknor & Fields to Louisa May Alcott 1863 August 25, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:221)
  - Howard M. Ticknor to Louisa May Alcott 1863 September 4, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 2:222)
  - H[oward] M. Ticknor to Louisa May Alcott 1865 June 21, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:223)
  - H[oward] M. Ticknor to Louisa May Alcott 1865 July 13, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:224)
  - H[oward] M. Ticknor to Louisa May Alcott 1866 September 7, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:225)
  - H[oward] M. Ticknor to Louisa May Alcott 1867 June 12, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 2:226)
  - Louisa May Alcott receipt to Ticknor & Fields 1867 June 15, ADS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:227)
  - G.M. Towle to Louisa May Alcott 1872 January [18], ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 2:228)
    with Louisa May Alcott draft on verso. 6255-b
  - William Hayes Ward to Louisa May Alcott 1874 March 12, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:229)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mrs. Waters [1887] December 7, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 2:230)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mrs. Wendte "Friday", ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 3:231)
  - Louisa May Alcott to "Dear Old Friend" with transcript [1877] December 16, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 3:232)
  - Louisa May Alcott to "Dear Sir" n.y. January 24, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 3:233)
  - Louisa May Alcott to "Gentlemen" n.y. April 30, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 3:234)
  - Louisa May Alcott to [ ? ] n.y. December 1, AN 1 p. (Box-folder 3:235)
  - Louisa May Alcott to "Dear Neighbor" n.d., ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 3:236)
  - Louisa May Alcott to [ ? ] n.d., ALS fragment 2 p. (Box-folder 3:237)
  - Louisa May Alcott to [ ? ] n.d., ANS 1 p. (Box-folder 3:238)
    6255-a
  - Louisa May Alcott to "Dear Sir" n.d., ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 3:239)
- Series III: Manuscripts
  - 10 lines, [regarding "Christie"] n.d., AMs fragment 1 p. (Box-folder 3:240)
  - 8 lines, "For Baby"s eldest babe..." n.d., AMs & auto. 1 p. (Box-folder 3:241)
  - Daisy's Ball, page 1 from Chap IX verso 1870, AMs 1 p. (Box-folder 3:242)
    1878 May 14 presentation note. 6255-c
  - poem: "My Laura" 1878 August 26, AMsS 3 p. (Box-folder 3:243)
  - poem [to T. Niles] 1885 January 1, AMsS 1 p. (Box-folder 3:244)
  - Jack and Jill, Chap 1, p. 2 n.d., AMs fragment 1 p. (Box-folder 3:245)
    6255-c
  - Jack and Jill, Chap 1, p. 10 n.d., AMs fragment 1 p. (Box-folder 3:246)
  - Jack and Jill, Chap 1, p. 14 & fragment n.d., AMs fragment 1 p. (Box-folder 3:247)
  - Jack and Jill, Chap 6, p. 91 n.d., AMs fragment 1 p. (Box-folder 3:248)
  - Jack and Jill, Chap 6, p. 95 n.d., AMs fragment 1 p. (Box-folder 3:249)
  - Jack and Jill, Chap 6, p. 97 n.d., AMs fragment 1 p. (Box-folder 3:250)
  - Jack and Jill, Chap 7, p. 98-100, 104-115 n.d., AMs fragment 15 p. (Box-folder 3:251)
  - Jack and Jill, Chap 8, p. 121 n.d., AMs fragment 1 p. (Box-folder 3:252)
  - Jack and Jill, Chap 8, p. 124 n.d., AMs fragment 1 p. (Box-folder 3:253)
    6255-d
  - Jack and Jill, Chap 9, p. 169-182 1880 May, AMs fragment 14 p. with typescript copy, 10 p. (Box-folder 3:254)
  - Jack and Jill, Chap 13 p. 203-222 1880 June, AMs fragment 20 p. with typescript copy, 15 p. (Box-folder 3:255)
  - Jack and Jill, p. 231 n.d., AMs fragment 1 p. and transcript p. 231-232, 1 p. (Box-folder 3:256)
  - Jack and Jill, p. 250 n.d., AMs fragment 1 p. (Box-folder 3:257)
  - Jack and Jill, Chap 15, p. 254 n.d., AMs fragment 1 p. (Box-folder 3:258)
    6255-f
  - Jo's Boys n.d., AMs fragment 1 p. (Box-folder 3:259)
  - "Lucian" with "An Apostrophe to Truth" with transcript and notes 1848 February 8 and June 11, AMs 8 p. (Box-folder 3:260)
  - Notes regarding Dr. Bartol's sermon on Abba Alcott n.d., AMs 2 p. (Box-folder 3:261)
  - Old Fashioned Girl, with miscellaneous fragments n.d., AMs 6 p. (Box-folder 3:262)
  - The Pickwick, No. I n.y. September 28, AMs 4 p. (Box-folder 3:263)
  - The Pickwick, No. II n.y. October 5, AMs 4 p. (Box-folder 3:263)
  - The Pickwick, No. III n.y. October 12, AMsS 4 p. (Box-folder 3:263)
  - "A Song to be Sung to the Tune of 'Polly Put the Kettle On'" or "My Laura," with transcript 1880 August 26, AMs 2 p. (Box-folder 3:264)
  - Spinning Wheel Stories, p. 1-45, [Story I: "Grandma's Story"] n.d., AMs 45 p. (Box-folder 3:265)
  - Spinning Wheel Stories, p. 46-90, [Story II: "Tabby's Tablecloth"] n.d., AMs 45 p. (Box-folder 3:266)
  - Spinning Wheel Stories, p. 91-137, [Story III: "Eli's Education"] [1884], AMs 47 p. (Box-folder 3:267)
  - Spinning Wheel Stories, p. 1-47, "Little Things" n.d., AMs 47 p. (Box-folder 3:268)
  - poem: "To Jack" n.d., AMs 1 p. (Box-folder 3:269)
  - "Two Little Travelers" n.d., AMsS 17 p. (Box-folder 3:270)
  - [unidentified, regarding postal stamps] n.d., AMs 1 p. (Box-folder 3:271)
  - quotations from various sources n.d., AMs 2 p. (Box-folder 3:272)
- Series IV: Photographs and Prints
  - Photograph of Louisa May Alcott - see also item 183
  - "Alcott House" with Louisa May Alcott portrait inset n.d., postcard (Box-folder 3:273)
  - "Orchard House, Home of the Alcotts..." n.d., postcard. (Box-folder 3:274)
  - 4 views of Orchard House n.d., photographs. (Box-folder 3:275)
  - "Wayside, the Home of Hawthorne" n.d., postcard (Box-folder 3:276)
  - view of Wayside n.d., photograph. (Box-folder 3:277)
  - John Sewell Pratt Alcott, with bicycle n.d., photograph (Box-folder 3:278)
  - Louisa May Alcott, left profile, from Sanborn photograph n.d., book illus. (Box-folder 3:279)
  - Louisa May Alcott, seated, by Norman, Boston n.d., photograph. (Box-folder 3:280)
  - Louisa May Alcott, left profile, Walton Ricketson, sculp. n.d., etching 2 copies. (Box-folder 3:281)
    6255-b (9521-h)
  - Louisa May Alcott, autographed 1865, silhouette. (Box-folder 3:282)
  - Louisa May Alcott, bust, Allen, Boston n.d., photographs, 2 copies. (Box-folder 3:283)
  - Louisa May Alcott, seated, with letter n.d., n.y. June 12, photograph. (Box-folder 3:284)
  - Louisa May Alcott, by S.W. Rowse n.d., portrait. (Box-folder 3:285)
    presented to the Louisa M. Alcott Club by The Mothers, 1905 March 23. 6255
  - Illustration for Little Women n.d., photograph. (Box-folder 3:286)
  - 5 illustrations from Moods n.d., book illus. (Box-folder 3:287)
  - Cabinet photograph of Louisa May Alcott, seated and holding a book, by A. Munroe, Concord, Mass. [ca. 1880], photograph. (Box-folder 3:288)
    6255-k
- Series V: Miscellaneous
  - Mimeographed list of Beatrice Gunn's Alcott Collection n.d., TM copy 21 p. (Box-folder 3:289)
  - Notice regarding "Bertha" and early works ca. 1850, printed. (Box-folder 3:290)
  - Reviews of Hospital Sketches 1863-1869, printed. (Box-folder 3:291)
  - Reviews of Moods (see also item 28) ca. 1864, printed. (Box-folder 3:292)
  - Reviews of Morning Glories ca. 1867, printed. (Box-folder 3:293)
  - Louisa May Alcott expense account for Concord Sketches 1870 February 11, AD 2 p. (Box-folder 3:294)
  - Reviews of An Old Fashioned Girl ca. 1870, printed. (Box-folder 3:295)
  - Reviews of Little Men ca. 1871, printed. (Box-folder 3:296)
  - Reviews of Little Women n.d., printed. (Box-folder 3:297)
  - Reviews of A Modern Mephistopheles ca. 1877, printed. (Box-folder 3:298)
  - Louisa May Alcott list of shares 1881, AD 6 p. (Box-folder 3:299)
  - Obituaries of Louisa May Alcott 1888, AMs/printed (Box-folder 3:300)
  - "In Memory of Louisa May Alcott by her friend, Anna Ricketson" 1888 April 29, TM copy 13 p. (Box-folder 3:301)
  - "The Copyright Law..." 1909, Pamphlet 40 p. (Box-folder 3:302)
  - Miscellaneous clippings and articles n.d., printed. (Box-folder 3:303)
  - "L.M. Alcott" with photocopy n.d., autograph. (Box-folder 3:304)